architecture ("way of houses") = nasin tomo
ask ("wanting to hear") = wile kute
boss ("leading person") = jan lawa
bridge ("connecting horizontal surface, thing to put or rest something on") = supa nasin
bum ("lower back") = monsi anpa
call ("try to talk to") = lukin toki
doctor ("person of health") = jan sona pi pona sijelo
exchange ("business transaction") = esun
fear ("bad feeling") = pilin ike
galaxy ("multitude of stars") = mute suno
god ("leading person of the heavens") = jan lawa sewi
guru ("person of knowledge") = jan sona
laugh ("playful emotional utterance") = a musi
marriage ("community of maritial relationship") = kulupu unpa
moon = mun
news = sona sin
planet ("night sky object") = mun
planet ("round world") = sike ma
pray ("try to talk to") = lukin toki
prevent ("remove the possibility") = weka e ken
religion ("doctrine of the divine") = nasin sewi
sculpture ("representation") = sitelen
smile ("happy face") = sinpin lawa pi pilin pona
space ship ("interstellar moving indoor space") = tomo tawa mun
star ("night sky object") = mun
star ("sun") = suno
sun = suno
temple ("house of religion") = tomo pi nasin sewi
ticket = lipu tawa
suno lon sewi pimeja li mute, a.
==There are so may stars in the sky
tenpo pini wan la sina lukin nanpa e ona?
==Have you ever tried to count it?
sina kama nanpa e ona, la sina wile awen lon sike suno pi mute ike.
==If you will start counting today then it will take 6000 years to
ni li suno mute pi mute mun ni taso.
==finish counting stars in only our galaxy
sin la mute suno ante li mute.
==and there a lot of such galaxies
jan sona li toki e ni.
==Scientist says that perhaps 2 billons more.
tan ni la ken la ni li lon anu seme: mute suno wan la sike ma wan la
==So isn't it possible that out of so many galaxies there is one planet out there
jan sama mi mute li lon?
==people like us exist.
mi mute li tawa mun li tawa sike ma ante.
==Just like we are traveling to moon and mars in order to reach them
ken la sama ni la
==There could be a possibilty
ona mute li lukin tawa mi mute li wile kama lukin e mi mute.
==They are also trying to reach us in order to spot our existence.
(kalama musi tan ilo)
==Song playing in a radio
jan akesi li weka e ilo lawa.
==The thing which thief has stolen was the remote control
kepeken ilo ni la jan li ken lon e tomo tawa mun.
==that is being used to relocate the space ship.
tan ni la ona li ken ala tawa sike ma ona.
==Without the remote control he can't go back to his home
ona li sona ala e toki pi mi mute.
==Neither he knew our language
sin la ona li jo ala e jan pona lon ni.
==Nor he had any friends here
ona li wan taso
==alone
li pilin ike.
==and frightened
ona li wile sona e ni taso: kepeken seme la ona li ken tawa tomo?
==he was thinking only one thing that how he'll return home now.
(Pachchan recites Pachchan.)
(jan Pasan li toki e sitelen pi jan Pasan.)
o weka e ike mi, taso mi sewi e luka mi lon tenpo nanpa wan.
==Sorry but i raised my hand first
a, taso mi kalama wawa lon tenpo nanpa wan. tan ni la...
==yeah but i shout for it first so..
o, mi olin e jan Aliwan Lawi Pasan.
==Look i am big fan of harivansh rai bacchan
taso mi sama li olin e jan Amita Pasan.
==but i am also a big fan of Amitabh bacchan
mi kama sona e nimi musi ona lon suli pi sike suno 10.
==I started reading his poems when i was 10.
mi kama musi e toki pi jan tu lon suli pi sike suno 5.
==I started practising his dialogues when i was 5
...ni la jan seme li wile e ona? sina pini e ni anu seme?
==..so who wants it..did you finalize yet?
jan o pana e ona tawa mi... jan ni li sona ala pilin e kon pi nimi musi.
==give it to me buddy..he won't understand a word of poetry.
Elo 100.
==100 euros.
Elo 100 lon esun pi lipu tawa pi Elo 40?
==100 euro for a 40 euro ticket?
sina lon esun pimeja e nimi musi??
==you are selling poetry in black??
mi awen lon kulupu pi jan awen lon tenpo suli. tenpo li mani.
==I stood 6 hours in the queue. Time is money.
sina o kute e toki pi jan tu.
==you go ahead listen dialogues.
ala. sina ken kama jo e ona. meli o nanpa wan.
==No no you can buy it. ladies first.
o awen lili. ken la mi tu o tu e mani pi lipu tawa anu seme?
==1 sec. why don't we share the price of tickets?
tenpo nanpa wan la sina ken kute e nimi musi. tenpo nanpa tu la mi ken kute e musi pi jan Amita.
==Before interval you can listen to your poems, and after that i can listen to amitabh's acting.
mi tu li jo e Elo 96. o lili e mani lon esun, jan o.
==we have 96 euro. give us a little discount pal
mi mute li tan ma sama. ma Palata o awen pona, jan sama o.
==after all we are from the same country. salute india bro!
ma mama o awen lon tenpo suli. Elo 100 taso li pona.
==vandematram. that'll be exact 100 euro.
jan suli o pana e Elo 4 esun. o?
==Uncle, could you give us a loan of 4 euro. please?
sina ken awen jo e ilo tenpo ni. tenpo suno kama la mi kama jo sin e ona lon esun pi mani esun.
==you can keep this watch, tomorrow i will take it back with borrowed money.
jan suli o, lipu tawa ni li nanpa ale.
==please uncle, its the last ticket.
insa tomo ale li jo e jan. lipu tawa ante li lon ala.
==its house full no ticket is available.
ala, jan suli o. lipu tawa wan li lon. jan wan li pana e ona lon esun pimeja.
==No uncle one ticket is available. one guy is selling it in black
jan akesi a!
==such a scoundrel
tan jan ni taso la ma mi li jo e nimi akesi.
==only because of such people our country is being denounced.
a.
==true
sina o awen taso lon ni. mi o kama jo e lipu tawa sina.
==you just wait there i will just get you your ticket.
jan seme?
==who?
sina toki seme kepeken nimi "jan seme"? lipu tawa mi?
==what do you mean who? my ticket?
lipu tawa.
==ticket.
a, lipu tawa... o pana e Elo 100 tawa mi.
==oh ticket..give me 100 euro
sina jan akesi, a!
==you fraud
tenpo ni la o tawa o lukin e jan Matusala...
==go now see madhushala..
jan pi suli ike o.
==old man
o tawa. ...o tawa.
==lets go ..lets go
jan suli pi sin ike o.
==bloody next generation old man
o weka taso e ike.
==just let it go now
kepeken seme la mi ken weka e ike? ni li ike pali.
==how could i let it go so easily.?
sona la ona li lon supa lon insa pi tomo ni li pilin pona tan nimi musi... taso mi lon ni...
==he must be sitting there and enjoying the poems..and i am here..
o weka taso e ike.
==just let it go.
jan li tawa weka tan kulupu, la ona li wile ala pilin ike.
==The gathering that abandon why to worry about it..
ona li ken pilin pona tan tenpo mute ante sin.
==there are yet some new moments to cherish let get along with it
mi ken lili sitelen musi.
==little bit i can also write
pona mute. o awen toki.
==its very good. tell me the next line.
ala.
==no i would not.
mi awen toki e pini pi nimi musi, la sina wile lon kulupu unpa lon poka mi.
==If i will narrate the further poem you will end up proposing me.
sina nasa anu seme?
==are you crazy?
mi toki pona!
==No really!
sina olin e jan musi Aliwan Lawi Pasan.
==your favorite poet is harivansh rai bacchan.
kama pi tenpo suno wan la ona li kama lon meli li toki e nimi musi ona tawa ona.
==In morning he met a woman, narrate her his poem
pini pi tenpo suno sama la ona tu li kama kulupu unpa.
==and in the evening he end up marrying her.
o lukin e ni:
==and now see..
ona li kama mama pi jan suli pona... jan Amita Pasan.
==..he gave birth to a legend..Amitabh bacchan
jan Jaku.
==jaggu
Jaku?
==jaggu?
a. ni li nimi mi.
==yes that's my name
sin la mama mi li pana e nimi ante pi nasa sin tawa mi.
==my dad gave me even more bizzare name
Jaka Jannani.
==jagat jannani
jan ale li musi ike kepeken mi lon tomo sona.
==everybody used to mock me at school
tan ni la mi lili e ona.
==therefore i made it short
Jaku.
==jaggu
sina tan ma tomo Munpawi anu seme?
==you from mumbai?
ala. Teli!
==Nope..Delhi!
ma tomo ni la mi lon tomo sona pi sitelen tawa.
==i am doing course of TV production here.
sina a?
==you?
mi jan Sapala...
==I am sarfaraz..
...mi kama sona e nasin tomo lon ni.
==..studying architecture here..
poka ni la mi pali...
==..and doing part-time job.
...lon tomo pi ma Pakitan.
==here itself in pakistan embassy.
lon tomo pi ma Pakitan? tan seme?
==...in pakistan embassy. why?
tan ni: mi tan ma Pakitan.
==because i am from pakistan.
sin la tomo pi ma Palata li wile ale e pali tan mi.
==Indian embassy wouldn't hire me afterall.
seme li kama?
==what happened?
ala.
==no, nothing.
mi tan ma Pakitan. sina kute e ni, la sinpin lawa sina pi pilin pona li kama weka.
==your smile disappered after you heard i am from pakistan.
o tawa?
==lets go?
mi tawa.
==khuda hafiz (good bye in urdu)
o weka e ma mama mi.
==Lets put our identity and tradition aside
o tawa lon poka mi.
==..and just walk together side by side.
o weka e ma mama mi.
==Lets put our identity and tradition aside
o tawa lon poka mi.
==..and just walk together side by side.
mi weka e suno pi wawa ike tan sina. mi lon sinpin ona.
==i'll give you shadow in the harsh sun light
pimeja li pana e pilin ike tawa sina, la
mi kule musi e mun tawa sina.
==if the darkness will scare you in farther sky,
i will decorate a moon for you
pilin ike li kama lon poka sina, la
mi toki musi tawa sina. mi pana e a musi tawa sina.
==if the sadness will surround you
i would tell you jokes and make you laugh
mi tu li awen jo e sinpin lawa pi pilin pona li awen tawa lon poka pi mi tu kepeken luka pi mi tu.
==we'll keep smiling and walking few steps
hand in hand.
ale li pana ala e pilin ike tawa mi tan ni: mi kama lon sina.
==the world doesn't scare me anymore after i met you.
mi lon, la mi ken tawa lon poka sina taso.
==Not just few steps i could walk with you my whole life.
pona!
==Thank you
mama meli o
==mummy
mama mije o... ona li kama olin
==papa..she's fallen in love
kama olin?
==fallen in love?
ona li suwi a.
==he's so cute.
o pana e sitelen sin.
==show us more pictures.
ona li pali e seme? ona o wile ala lon tomo pi kulupu mama.
==what does he do? i hope not from a joint family
o toki ala. mi toki e ale.
==stay calm, i will tell everything.
nanpa wan la o toki e nimi ona.
==first tell us his name.
Sapala.
==sarfaraz.
ona li jan Musuman anu seme?
==he is muslim?
a, mama mije o. ona li kama sona e nasin tomo lon ni.
taso kulupu mama ona li lon ma Pakitan.
==yes papa. he is studying architure here.
but family is in pakistan.
Pakitan?
==pakistan?
sina toki e seme? sina wile jo e len lon sinpin lawa anu seme? lukin e sitelen pi nasin sewi Musuman? sina kama nasa!
==what are you saying? you are going to wear burka? read namaz?
you have gone insane
jan Jaku o awen ni taso. o tawa ala weka.
o pana e tomo tawa mi... lon tenpo ni.
==jaggu you stay right there, don't disconnect.
take out my car..quickly.
pakala li kama. o pana e pona, jan sona Si o.
==its been a disaster, please help us guruji.
mi sona e tawa pi mama mije mi.
==I knew where my father was going.
tenpo pini la mi en jan sama mi li lili. ni la mi tu li lukin e sinpin lawa pi jan sona Si lon tenpo mute e sinpin lawa pi mama tu mi lon tenpo lili.
==Since childhood we saw face of tapasvi guru ji face
more than our parents.
supa ale li jo e sinpin lawa ona.
==from school bag to bather wall he was present everywhere.
sin la ona li kama jo ala e toki pi pona kama tan jan sona Si, la ona li wile ala tawa jan pi pona pi kiwen uta.
==he wouldn't even go to dentist without taking a auspicious advise from guruji.
jan Si li pana e poki. insa ona li lon jan lawa sewi mute. ona mute li ilo pi pali ale.
==tapasvi ji presented my dad a box in which there was a
favorable god for each and every task.
ona li lon esun mani kepeken ilo sona, la
ona li pana e lukin pi ilo sitelen tawa jan lawa sewi Lami.
==when he was doing share trading he used
to show laxmi godess sculpture to the computer screen.
ona li tawa li pona e sijelo ona, la
jan lawa sewi Hanuman li lon.
==and when he was on treadmill
there was a hanuman ji sculpture.
toki sewi kepeken ilo sona, lukin sewi, moku sewi kepeken jan tawa. ale ni li wile pi jan lawa Si.
==Internet prayer, auspicious sight, prasad via courier.
it was all tapasvi ji's idea.
jan Jaku o luka e noka ona o kute e toki sewi ona.
==jaggu touch his feet and take his blessings
tan seme, jan Jaka Jannani o? tan seme la sina wile moli e sina?
==why jagat janani? why you want to do suicide?
o kama jo e ilo sitelen o sitelen e ijo.
==grab a pen and a paper and write.
jan lawa sewi o, o lawa e mi.
==God...show me the way.
sina wile e ni, la.
==as you wish.
o sitelen e toki pi ijo kama, jan Jaka Jannini o.
==write the future prediction jagat janani.
mije Sapala tan ma Pakitan li wile toki pi lawa ike tawa sina.
==The guy from pakistan named sarfaraz will deceive you.
ona li ni ala.
==No he won't
sina lukin e tenpo pini, la tenpo ala la ona mute li toki pi lawa pona.
==if you look at the past they have never been honest
ona li kepeken sijelo sina, taso tenpo ala la ona li kama lon kulupu unpa lon poka sina. a, pini pi tenpo lili la ona li tawa weka tan sina.
==he will use your body but never going to marry you.
infact he will leave you soon.
jan Jaku o tawa sin tawa ma Palata lon tenpo ni.
sina awen lon ni lon tenpo pimeja sin, la...
==jaggu, come back to India right away.
If you will stay one more night there..
sina meli lili mi ala.
==you will no longer be my daughter.
jan Sani o, mi o toki tawa ona.
==Mr. sahni, let me speak with her
jan lili o weka e ona tan lipu sona lon insa pi lawa sina...
==child, just press the delete button..
o weka e ona tan ilo sona lon insa pi ale sina.
==and disconnect him out of your life.
seme li lon?
==what's going on?
sina olin e mi anu seme?
==do you love me?
olin, a. tan seme?
==ofcourse i do. why?
sina kama kulupu unpa lon poka mi anu seme?
==Will you marry me?
o, seme li lon?
==but what happend?
o toki e nimi "a" anu nimi "ala".
==just yes or no?
a, taso...
===yes but..
tenpo suno kama la.
==tomorrow.
tenpo suno kama?
==tomorrow?
tenpo suno kama la mi tu li kama kulupu unpa.
==tomorrow we will get married.
jan Si li toki ike e tenpo kama.
==Tapasvi ji's prediction is false.
mi pana e lukin.
==I'll prove it.
pona tawa sina!
==Congratulation.
ni li lipu tan jan Sapala.
==It was sarfaraz's letter.
ona li toki e ni: kulupu unpa li kama lon insa pi kulupu mama tu.
==he wrote that marriage happend between two families.
ma mama mi, jan ona en nasin sewi ona, ale li ante.
==Our country, people and religion everything is different.
mi tu li ken ala pilin pona lon pilin ike pi kulupu mama pi mi tu. o lukin ala tawa mi. o weka e ike mi.
==We can not be happy by making our family unhappy.
don't try to contact me. sorry.
mi lon ma tomo mi,
taso @ mi wile ala e ni: mi lon tomo.
==I was in my city,
but my didn't let me stay in the house.
mi kama lon kulupu pali. ona li pana e sona sin kepeken sitelen tawa.
==I joined a news channel.
jan lawa mi li wile pana e sona sin pi soweli pi pilin ike.
==Boss caught a depressed a dog for breaking news.
tenpo wan la mi mute li kama jo e sona sin,
tenpo ante la mi mute li pali e sona sin.
==sometimes we used to get news,
sometimes create news.
weka ike. lukin la o toki tawa jan Na Sa.
==Missing. If found contact PK.
mi kama lukin e sona sin. o tawa tomo pali.
mi lon ni lon pini pi tenpo lili.
==I found a story, you reach office
I will be there soon.
o tawa lon tenpo lili.
==come quickly.
o weka e ike mi?
==Excuse me?
tan seme la sina pana e lipu ni?
==Why are you distributing these brochures?
mi wile pini pali e ijo lon poka pi jan lawa sewi.
==One of my case is pending with God.
ona li pini ala e ni. taso mi ken ala kama lukin e ona.
==Neither he resolved nor be found.
pakala.
==its been a mess.
mi sona ala e ni: seme la ona li kama weka.
==don't where he disappeared.
sina kama lukin e ona lon ijo?
==Have you seen him somewhere?
ala.
==No.
[kalama musi pi nasin sewi li tan ilo.]
==[Religious song playing on a radio].
tan seme la lawa sina li jo e len kiwen?
==Why are you wearing this helmet?
tan tomo tawa esun la mi kama sona e ni: ijo li jelo lon ijo ante mute a, la jan li ken kama lukin e ona.
==I learned from taxi, even in heavy traffic
it can be spotted from long distance because of flashy yellow color.
tan ni la seme?
==so?
tan ni la jan lawa sewi li ken kama lukin e mi lon kulupu suli a.
==So it will be easy for the God also to spot me in heavy crowd.
jan toki e ni: soweli li moli ala e ona sama.
==They say that animals don't suicide.
ni li soweli Niku. jan Suwisi Sin li jo e ona
lon ma Lame Naka pi ma tomo Teli.
==Its a dog named nikku of sweeti singh
who lives in ramesh nagar in delhi.
tenpo mun pini la tenpo 3 la ona li lukin moli e ona sama.
==it did three suicide attempts in past one month.
ona li anpa e ona sama tan sewi li uta e ilo lape li lon ilo seli e ona sama.
==It tried jumping from the terrace, licking a sleeping pills
and jumping on a gas burner.
soweli Niku li pali e ni tan seme?
==Why did nikku do this?
ona li jo e lawa ike anu seme?
==Is nikku suffering from a mental disorder?
[mu lili pi pilin ike]
==[dog whining]
jan Jaku o, seme li kama?
==what happened jaggu?
jan mute li sona e jan Latan Ataliwa. ona li lawa e tomo pali. pini pi tenpo lili la mi mute li awen toki tawa ona.
==We'll continue talking to famous industrialist
Mr ratan atarival after a short break..
sina wile e telo wawa anu seme?
==you want coffee?
jan o pana e telo wawa tawa mije ni!
==someone get gentleman a coffee.
pakala...
==oh no
tawa sina la ona li pilin ike tan seme? tan weka wawa? tan ala? tan kon nasa? tan weka olin?
==What do you think it has depression,
anxiety disorder, schizophrenia or
attention deficit hyperactivity disorder?
mi wile ala sona e ike ona.
==What ever it has why would i care?
lon! jan ala li wile sona!
==exactly. Why would anyone care?
ni la tan seme la mi mute li pana e sona sin nasa ni
lon tomo pi sitelen tawa, pi mi mute?
==then why are we showing such stupid news
on our channel?
sina wile pana e seme a?
==so what do you want to show?
o jo e ona lon tenpo lili.
==Can you hold it for a sec?
o lukin e ni. tenpo suno ni la mi kama sona
e mije. ona li pana e lipu ni. ona li wile kama lukin e sewi.
==Look at this I met a man today who is
distributing pamphlets. seaching God.
ona li kama lukin anu seme?
==Did he found?
ala. taso...
==No..but..
jan li wile kama lukin e jan lawa sewi, la ni li nasin sewi. ona li kama lukin, la ni li sona sin.
==Seaching God is religion, Finding God is news.
ona li kama lukin e jan lawa sewi, la o kama e ona. mi pana e sitelen ona.
==When he found the God bring him here i will put him on air.
taso
==but
sina sona e nasin lawa pi kulupu ni.
o toki ala e sona sin pi nasin sewi, pi jan lawa sewi. pini.
==you know the company policy.
No news on religion and no news on god.Finish.
seme li kama tawa sina? kon utala sina li tawa seme?
==What happened to you? where did your fighting spirit go?
sina wile lukin e jan utala anu seme? ona li lon ni.
==you want to see fighter? here it is.
sina wile lukin e pakala pi monsi anpa mi anu seme?
==should I show you the marks on my bum?
mi jo ala e ni tan kama tan lupa pi mama meli mi.
sina sona e jan Si, jan pi pona mute, pi mama mije sina. jan tan toki ona li pali e ni kepeken ilo utala pi nasin sewi tan ni:
==Its not birth marks.
The follower of your dad's dearest friend tapasvi guru
did this with trishul weapon.
mi pana e sona sin pi ijo ike pi jan Si.
==..when i broadcasted the news against him.
tan tenpo suno ni la mi wile awen lon ma ni,
la mi wile toki ala e ijo pi nasin sewi.
==That day i decided if i want to stay in this country
i should avoid messing up with religion..
jan lawa mi li weka e ken ni: mi toki e sona sin ni.
==boss didn't let me follow up that story.
taso pini pi tenpo esun tu la mi tawa, la mi kama lukin e sona sin ni lon tenpo sin.
==..but after 2 weeks i found that story
once again on the way.
jan akesi! jan akesi!
==Robber!  Robber!
jan o alasa e ona! ona li akesi li tan poki e mani tawa ona sama.
==Somebody catch him, He is stealing money from
the donation box.
o, sina tawa seme? o awen!
==hey where you going? wait!
o alasa e ona.
==catch him.
o tawa weka.
==Get away.
jan nasa o! sina lon poki pi jan lawa sewi e luka?
==fool! you putting hands in God's pocket?
jan pi sona kama o, ona li jan akesi ala.
==pandit ji, he is not a thief.
mi lon poki e mani, taso poki mani mi li kama anpa tawa insa ona.
==I was putting money in donation box but my purse fell in it.
ona li pana e pona taso tawa mi, kepeken ni mi ken tan insa e ona.
==He was just helping me to take it out.
ona li toki e lon.
==its true.
sina ken kama sona e ni.
==you can check it.
poki mani li jo e Lupi 5000. sina ken kama sona.
==purse has around 5000 rupees. you can check.
jan pi sona kama o, ni li ijo mi.
==pundit ji. that's mine.
lon tenpo pini a! sina pana e ona tawa poki. jan ken ala pana sin e ona.
==It was. once donated can't be returned.
ona o ken tawa.
==Let them go.
o!
==hey
taso sina pali e seme a?
==but what was you doing exactly?
mi wile e mani mi.
==I was taking back my refund.
tenpo pini la mi pana e mani tawa ona, taso ona li pali ala tawa mi.
==He took the payment but didn't do my job.
o awen lili.
==hang on a sec.
tenpo nanpa wan la mi lukin e ni: sina tan insa e mani. ni la sina pana sin e ona anu seme?
==I saw first you took out some money
and then put it back?
tomo pali ni la mi pana e Lupi 200.
mi tan e mani ni taso.
==In this office department (temple) i only deposited 200 rupees.
Rest i put it back.
tenpo pini la sina jo e ijo mute pi nasin sewi.
==you had lots of holy amulets and talisman
in your neck?
mi wile ala jo e ona.
==I rejected. Won't wear no more.
ni la tan seme la sina jo e sitelen pi jan lawa sewi?
==then why you have god stickers on you?
mi weka e ike tan mi.
==Self-defense.
sama ni la jan li lon sinpin tomo e sitelen pi jan lawa sewi.
kepeken ni la jan ala li pana e telo jaki tawa ona.
==Just like they put god picture on wall
so that nobody urinate on it.
mi lon ni e ona. kepeken ni la jan ala li pakala e mi.
==I put it here so that nobody hit me.
jan Mitu o, sina lon seme?
==meetu. where are you?
sina ken tawa e mi anu seme? mi jo ala e mani. mi ken ala tawa tomo.
==Can you pick me up? i don't have money to go home.
mi lon sinpin pi tomo suli pi nasin sewi.
==i am in mudrika opposite the big temple.
o kama lon tenpo lili. mi awen.
==come quickly thanks bye.
o jo e ni.
==here, take this.
tan seme?
==why?
kepeken ni la sina ken tawa tomo.
==for taxi.
mi pilin ike lon ni:
jan li ken ala tawa tomo.
==I don't feel good when somebody
unable to return home.
o kute...
==listen..
mi jo ala e mute sin. ni li ale.
==don't have more. that was it.
ala. mi ken ala tan e ona.
==no no. i cant take this.
tan seme?
==why?
sina sama li wile e ni. kepeken ni la sina ken tawa tomo.
==you must need this to get back home yourself.
mani li ken ala pana e pona tawa mi.
==Money can't help me.
tan seme? tomo sina li lon seme?
==Why? where do you live?
mi awen lon tomo Akasen Ki Pajoli,
taso tenpo suno mute ni la tenpo mute la telo li kama lon anpa tan sewi.
tan ni la tenpo la mi kepeken tomo pi lupa ala.
==Although i stay in Agrasen's Baoli,
However as its raining often now-a-days so
i check in sometimes in lock up.
tomo pi jan pali pi nasin lawa?
==Lock up as in police lock up?
a. ma tomo Teli la tomo 122 li lon. mi awen sin e nanpa.
==yeah in delhi they have 122. I keep going in rotation.
sina kama pona tawa ona anu seme?
==..and they let you check in like a hotel?
o kama. mi pana e sona.
==come, i will explain.
ni la jan li ken ala pana e telo jaki
==-Urinating here is prohibited-
sina o awen lon ni.
==you stay here.
jan pali pi nasin lawa o lukin!
==hey thulley(cop), Look!
o awen lili. mi pana e lukin tawa sina.
==wait, i'll show you.
jan Jaku o!
==jaggu.
o lon monsi. mi wile tawa lon monsi pi tomo tawa ni.
==sit back, we need to follow that car.
jan seme li lon tomo tawa ni?
sona sin.
==but who is in the car?
Story!
tenpo ni la o pana e mani.
pona. mi tawa.
==quickly.. give me some money.
thanks bye.
mi wile tawa insa.
==I need to go inside.
tan seme?
==why?
mi wile toki tawa jan ni.
==I want to meet that man.
tawa sina la ni li tomo moku anu seme?
ni li tomo pi lupa ala.
==Its not a college canteen where you can
go in and have a refreshment. its a lock up.
jan akesi taso li ken tawa insa. sina sona e ni anu seme?
==Only people who do crime can go in. understand?
jan o, jan li ken ala pana e mani tawa jan pali pi nasin lawa.
==madam, bribery is a crime.
tan ni la mi jan akesi.
==its a crime that's why i am.
mi ken lon insa e sina.
==i can put you in.
o pana e pona ni.
==please do.
lon awen pi tenpo lili taso.
==only one hour.
toki! mi wile kama sona e pini sina. sina toki e ona anu seme?
==hi, i want to know your story. will you tell me?
tan seme?
==why?
mi pana e sona sin lon tomo pi sitelen tawa. ni li pali mi.
==i am a TV reporter. It's my job.
sina wile sona e seme?
==Ask what you want to.
nimi sina li seme?
==So what is your name?
mi jo ale e nimi. taso mi sona ala e ni: tan seme la jan ale li kepeken nimi "Na Sa" tawa mi.
==I don't have a name. but not sure why everyone call me PK.
sina seme?
==what do you do?
mi jan mun.
==I am astronomer.
jan mun? sina tawa mun anu seme?
==astronaut? people who go to moon?
tenpo wan la mi lon ni. ni la ala li kama.
==I have been there once. its absolutely dull place.
a, tawa sina la sike ma li pona nanpa wan?
==ok, so what's your favorite planet?
sike ma mi.
==Our own one.
tawa mi la mi sona a. taso sike ma pi pona nanpa wan li sike Ma ala, la ona la seme?
==thats for sure but apart from earth?
sike ma ni li pakala. mi toki e ijo pi ma sike mi.
==Earth is banged up. i said my own planet.
tenpo pimeja la jan li ken lukin e ona lon sewi.
==when its night its visible up there.
sike ma ante li lon. ona li sama sike ma pi mi mute.
jan sama mi mute li lon ona. mi mute li kama sona e ni, la
jan ale li kama nasa.
==..we had a huge fuzz that day when
we found there is similar planet like ours exist.
where people like us live.
ona mute li tawa ni e mi. kepeken ni mi ken kama sona.
taso ike li kama. jan akesi li weka e ilo lawa pi tomo tawa mun mi.
==they sent me here to do research, but
shockingly somebody stole my spaceship's remote control.
kepeken ona taso la mi ken toki tawa tomo.
==Without it i can't send signal home.
mi ken ala pana e toki, la jan ala li tawa ni li tawa tomo e mi.
==and if i won't send signal nobody will come here to
take me back.
tawa ona la mi kama moli lon sike ma akesi ni.
==They'll think its a dangerous planet and i died here.
o kute, o open e lupa. mi wile tawa tomo.
==listen, open the gate i want to go home.
sina lawa ala e ni.
==leave that up to us.
mi jan akesi ala.
==i am not a thief.
a, jan akesi ale li toki sama.
==yes, all thief say the same thing.
jan Pante Si li lon seme? o lukin toki tawa ona.
==where is pandey ji. call him.
ona li lon ala.
==he's not here.
jan Pante Si o.
==pandey ji.
jan Pante Si o!
meli lili o kalama ala. ante la...
==pandey ji!
hey girl, keep quiet or else..
tawa sina la toki mi li nasa anu seme?
==you think my story is nonsense?
a, toki sina li ken ala toki Palata.
==yes, your planet language can't be bhojpuri.
sike ma mi li jo ala e ...
==our ball doesn't even..
sike ma mi li jo ala e toki.
mi mute li toki kepeken kon. toki ike li ken lon ala.
==our ball doesn't even have any language.
we talk with mind. no room for confusion.
ma sike ni la jan li toki e ijo wan li wile toki e kon pi ijo ante.
==here they say something and mean something else.
toki wan li ken jo e kon 4 ante.
==one statement has four meanings.
jan li tawa lili e lawa ona li toki "a", la
ona li toki e ni: ale li pona.
==shake your head like this and
say its good..very good. means all is well.
jan li suli e lukin li toki "a", la
ona li toki e ni: ona li pilin ike.
==make the eyes bigger and say "accha" it means
someone is in shock.
"mama sina li kama pakala."
"a?" - pilin ike.
=="your mother had an accident".
"accha"? - Shock
jan li kama pilin utala, la kalama li kama suli.
"a?" "sina wile pana e sona tawa mi anu seme?"
==when one gets angry, voice becomes loud.
"accha"? "you are teaching me"?
jan li kepeken lawa, la "a" li awen lon tenpo suli.
==and once someone thinks. there is a long "accha."
"aaa"
=="acchaaa"
nasin toki li suli sama. ale li ike tawa lawa mi.
mi wile awen lon tenpo pimeja wan. kepeken ni la mi kama sona e toki Palata.
==With words you need to learn the expressions as well.
it was so damn confusing. took me 6 hours to learn bhojpuri.
sina toki e ni anu seme: sina kama sona e ale pi toki Palata lon awen pi tenpo pimeja wan.
==you mean in 6 hours you learned complete
bhojpuri?
jan ale li wile e ni: mi ken luka e luka ona.
taso tenpo ante la mi kama lukin e meli. ona li pali lon poka mi.
==Nobody was letting me hold their hand.
but then i found a lady who co-operated with me.
mi jo e luka ona. mi kama jo e ale toki.
==I hold her hand and transffered the whole language
to me.
sina ken ala pini toki ike anu seme?
o pini.
==hey you just can't stop blabbering.
put some limit to your lie.
luka sina li ilo linja, kepeken ona la sina ken pana e lipu sona tan ilo sona wan tawa ilo sona ante anu seme?
==Is your hand a USB cable that you can transfer
file like one computer to another? huh?
seme li ijo pi len sina? sama la jan lon sike ma sina
li jo e len noka tan tomo pali suli?
==and what about your cloths? People in your planet
also wear branded jeans?
ala. sike ma mi la jan ala li jo e len.
==No No..in our ball nobody wears cloths.
mi kama lon ni, la tenpo wan la tawa mi la
jan li jo e selo ante.
==At first when i came here i thought people here
have different skin.
selo pi jan wan li suno. selo pi jan ante li pimeja.
==some have shining skin, some have black.
selo wan li kule. selo ante li walo.
==some colorful and some absolutely white.
selo wan li lipu. selo ante li nena.
==some skin were tacky, some loose.
tenpo suno wan la mi kama lukin e tomo tawa... pi tawa musi.
==then one day i found a car..dancing car.
tenpo suno ni la mi kama sona e ni: jan li jo e selo sama mi.
==That day i realized people here have similar skin like us.
taso ona li lon sijelo e ijo pi nimi "nasin len".
==They just put some objects known as fashion
around their body.
tenpo ni la sama la mi ken kama lon jan
pi sike ma sina.
==Now i could also meet with people
from your planet ball.
taso mi sona ala e ni: tan seme la jan ale li a musi tawa mi.
==but not sure why everyone was laughing at me.
mi wile e tenpo lili, kepeken ona mi kama sona e ni:
meli en mije li jo e nasin len ante.
==took a little time to understand that male and female
had separate fashion.
kama pi tenpo suno en tenpo pimeja li jo e nasin len ante.
==Morning and night fashion was different.
jan wan li tawa li pona e sijelo ona, la ona li jo e nasin len wan.
jan ante li moku e telo nasa, la ona li jo e nasin len ante.
==Playing sports and having toast fashion was different.
poka len la mi kama lukin e sitelen.
==With cloths i also found a picture.
tenpo suli taso la mi kama sona e ni: sitelen ni li suli mute.
kepeken ona la mi ken lon weka tan moli lon sike ma ni.
==I slowly realized that this photo is very important
in order to survive on this ball.
esun pi sitelen ni la jan li ken kama jo e moku.
tan ni la mi alasa e sitelen pi jan suli ni.
==In exchange to this photo, food to eat can be earned.
hence i started collecting photos of this famous personality.
seme?
==what?
tan seme la sina pana e ni tawa mi?
==why you giving me this?
tan seme la sina pana e jaki lon esun mi?
==why you giving junk in my shop?
a, o pana e ni. ni li tawa sina. kili palisa.
==aha, give me that. there you go, carrots.
mi kama jo e pilin ni: lipu pi nasin wan taso la
sitelen ni li jo e suli.
==then i got this feeling that the value of this photo
is only on one kind of paper.
lipu ante la suli ona li ala.
==on other papers the value is zero.
mi kama jo e len ante tan tomo tawa pi tawa musi.
==then gradually i managed to get cloths from dancing car.
tenpo wan la mi kama lukin e len pi pona ni:
mi wile ala e mani, kepeken ona mi kama jo e moku.
==once i found such a wonderful attire that i
didn't even need the paper with photo to get food.
tan ona sama la moku li tawa mi.
==food came flying to me irresistibly.
mi wile kama jo e toki pi sike ma ni,
kepeken ni la mi ken kama jo sin e ilo lawa mi.
==Now inorder to get my remote back i needed to learn
this ball's language.
ni la kepeken toki taso la ijo li ken kama.
==without language nothing was possible here.
ijo pi kon sama la mi ken ala toki tawa mije ni e ni:
tawa mi la nasin len ona li pakala.
==for example telling this gentleman that i think
his fashion may have some defect.
mi pilin e ni: mi pakala e nasin len ona.
==I felt i messed up his fashion.
tan ni la mi pona sin e ona.
==that's why i recorrected.
mi kama lukin e ona lon nasin. jan jaki li pakala e ona li tawa weka.
==I found him on road, some jerk hit and ran.
tawa mi la ona li pona, taso ona li toki sin ala.
==seems alright but he doesn't response.
ken la kute ona li kama pakala?
==perhaps he's gone deaf?
jan pi kute pakala o!
ona li kute, taso ona li toki sin ala.
==hey deaf!
he does hear but not answering.
tawa mi la ona li awen jo e pilin ike. sin la sona ona li kama weka.
==i think he had a shock, and now memory loss.
sina awen sona e jan, ona li pakala e sina?
==do you remember who hit you?
sina awen sona e lipu nimi pi tomo tawa
anu seme wan?
==do you remember the vehicle's number or
anything at all?
o tawa lon poka mi.
==come with me.
sina kama pona lon mi lon awen pi weka pi sona sina.
==you are my guest until your memory comes back.
o awen pakala e lawa sina. pakala li ken weka e sona, la
sama la pakala li ken lon sin e ona.
==keep banging your head, if a hit can take memory away
it can return the same way too.
mi lukin e ni lon sitelen tawa.
==I saw it in films.
kepeken ni la mi ken kama sona e kon pi toki ona:
mi wile luka e luka ona, mi wile kama jo e toki.
==In order to understand what he was saying i needed
to grab his hand and transfer the language.
a! sona sina li kama weka. mije en meli li ante.
sona ni sin li weka anu seme?
==woah! Memory lost and you forgot the difference between
male and female?
o awen lili. o lukin e lipu tawa mi.
mije anu meli - mije, MIJE, MI-JE...
==one second, have a look at my license.
sex - male, man, mister, jerk, bastard..
kepeken ni mi ken tawa tomo: mi wile luka
e luka jan. ni li suli nanpa wan.
==inorder to go back home, holding someone's hand
was a priority now.
jan mi pi kama pona, pi pilin pona li kama.
==here comes our jaunty guest.
ona li lukin ala e ante pi mije anu meli.
==who doesn't differentiate male or female.
==tawa meli lili pi kama pona la unpa li pona.
licentious boy visited us as a guest.
mi ken pilin e pilin ike sina, taso o luka ala
e luka pi jan ante lon lukin pi jan ale.
==i can understand your pain, but don't hold anyone's
hand here in public.
mi sona e ni: tenpo la pona li kama,
taso sina ken kama pakala.
==I know sometimes luck can favor,
but your life could get in danger.
o pilin ike ala. pona. o tawa lon poka mi.
==don't be sad, ok come with me.
ni la sina ken luka e luka anu noka pi jan ante.
jan ala li utala e sina.
==here you can hold anybody's hand or leg,
nobody is going to assault you.
ni li tomo pi pona mute. jan ale li pona lukin li pona...
==This place was a paradise, everyone was very beautiful
and friendly..
jan ale li wile luka e luka mi li tawa tomo ona e mi.
tenpo ni la mi kama lon meli pona pi kiwen ala mute.
nimi ona li Pusalija.
==everybody wanted to hold my hand and take me to their home.
then i met a very gentle and calm minded lady
named phuljhariya.
jan Pusalija o tawa tomo pi kulupu unpa e ona.
==phuljhariya, take him to the honeymoon suite.
ona li wile pana e tenpo ona. awen pi
tenpo pimeja la mi tan e sona toki.
==she showed tremendous patience, and I
till 6 hours kept transffering the language.
wan, tu, mute, a, e, o. mi tan insa ona e ale.
==1, 2, 3, XYZ everything inside her i pulled everything.
tenpo nanpa wan anu seme?
==first time?
ilo sina li kama pakala lon kama pali anu seme?
==your bulb fused before even started. eh?
a...
==yea..
tomo sina li lon seme?
==where do you live?
mi tan weka, meli o.
==I came from far away miss.
ken la sina sona ala e tomo mi.
==you might not have even heard about
my village.
taso toki sina li sama toki mi.
==your language is just like mine though.
mi kama sona tan meli sama sina. tan ni.
==i learned from you sister that's why.
o, meli sama? o toki pona!
==hey.. sister? mind your language.
o kama weka!
==get lost!
jan sama o! jan sama o pini lape!
brother! wake up brother!
sina kama toki a!
==you started talking!
o pana e pona tawa mi, jan sama o.
==I need your help brother.
jan Pusalija li pali e wawa sewi seme tawa sina?
==what magic phuljhariya did on you?
o tawa wawa lon poka mi.
==come with me quickly
lukin la sona li lon poka unpa.
==Apparently there is a direct connection
between memory and sex.
mi wile toki e ni tawa jan sona pi pona sijelo.
kepeken ilo ni pi pilin pona la jan li ken pona e sijelo.
==We have to tell this to the doctor.
The most delighted operation of pleasure.
ijo li suli mute. o pana e pona
o tawa lon poka mi. tenpo li lili.
==There is a very important thing.. please
come with me. hurry up.
o awen... o awen!
==stop..stop!
jan sama o, jan akesi ni li weka e len linja mi
lon ni a.
==brother, that culprit snatched my necklace chain
right at this spot.
mi wile e len linja ni, jan sama o.
==I need that chain brother.
ona li ijo pi mani suli anu seme?
==Is it expensive?
mani pi suli mute.
==Very expensive.
taso jan akesi li tan ma tomo mi, la
ona li wile weka tan jan pali pi nasin lawa.
li lukin lon esun e ilo lawa lon ma tomo Teli.
==its highly possible that thief is from our village.
but as anyone can get caught easily here he
must have tried to sell it in delhi
tan ni la mi wile tawa.
==So i have to go brother.
tawa seme?
==where?
ma tomo Teli.
==Delhi.
mije o.
a?
jan akesi li weka e ilo lawa mi.
==Mister.
yes?
My remote control has been stolen.
sina jan nasa anu seme?
ilo lawa pi ilo pi sitelen tawa li suli ala
tawa jan pali pi nasin lawa.
==Are you PK (drunk)?
Police have no other work to do then
finding people's tv remote?
ni li ilo lawa pi ilo pi sitelen tawa ala.
==It wasn't tv remote.
taso?
==then?
mi ken toki ala. taso ona li len linja
pi mani mute.
==that i can't tell. but it was a very
expensive necklace.
jan akesi li weka e ona lon seme?
==Where it was stolen?
ma tomo Mantawa. ma Rasatan.
==in mandava. Rajasthan.
jan nasa o! ona li kama weka lon ma tomo Mantawa,
taso sina wile kama lukin e ona lon ma tomo Teli?
==Idiot ! It was stolen in mandava and you are
finding it in delhi?
a, taso jan akesi li tawa ma tomo Teli.
==yes but that theif came to delhi.
tan ni la seme?
==so?
jan li ken kama lukin e ona lon ni.
==he'll be found here.
jan nasa o! mute jan pi ma tomo ni li 15.000.000.
jan pali pi nasin lawa li jan taso li jan lawa sewi ala.
==chucklehead! the population of this city is 1.5 crore.
Police is also human not God.
jan lawa sewi taso li ken pana e pona tawa sina.
==Now only God can help you.
o toki pona e ijo pi jan lawa sewi.
ona taso li ken pana e lukin pi nasin pona.
==Praise the God only he can show you
the right way.
jan lawa sewi taso li sona e lon ona.
==Only God knows where to find it.
jan lawa sewi li sona... o kama weka.
==Only God would know..Now get lost.
o awen pilin e pona pi jan lawa sewi, jan lili o.
==Have faith in God son.
jan lawa sewi ni li jan seme? ona li ken pana e pona tawa mi.
jan ale li awen toki e nimi ona.
==Who is this God who can help me.
everyone is blabbering its name.
ni li sona sin wawa tawa mi.
jan pi sike ma ni li sona e jan ni, ona li pali e sike ma ona.
==What is saw blew my mind.
The people of this ball knew who manufactured there planet.
a, jan lawa sewi ni li lon tomo lon poka ona.
nasin ale la ona li jo e tomo.
==Infact he(God) was living with them only.
In every street he had his house.
jan pi mute suli li tawa tomo ona li pana e mani lili.
jan lawa sewi li weka e pilin ike ona ale.
==Million of people go to his house with small
fee and he takes away all their trouble.
sike ma mi la wawa sewi ni li lon ala.
==Such magic and miracle is not in my planet.
tawa mi la ni li nasa. mi pilin e ni:
mi o lukin.
==I couldn't believe. I thought of giving
it a try.
sina ken pana e jan lawa sewi tawa mi anu seme?
==Could you give me a god?
jan lawa sewi seme? ni pi Lupi 20 anu Lupi 50 anu Lupi 100 anu Lupi 500?
==Which one? 20 one? 50 one? 100 one or 500 rupee one?
seme li ante pi Lupi 20 anu Lupi 500?
==what is the difference in 20 one and 500 rupee one?
suli taso li ante. ale ante li sama.
==Only size difference. rest is same.
ni la ni pi Lupi 20 li pona sama anu seme?
==So the 20 rupee one works just fine as well. right?
o jo e ni. o pana e Lupi 15. o jo o tawa.
==here, give 15 rupees. just take and go.
jan lawa sewi o, mi wile moku.
o pana e moku tawa mi.
==God i am starving.
Let me get something to eat.
mi kama nasa. jan lawa sewi ni li ilo.
==I went totally nut. this God seemed to be
working.
tenpo ni la mi ken tawa tomo.
==Now i could go back my home.
jan lawa sewi o, ilo lawa mi li kama weka tan jan akesi.
o pana e ona tawa mi. mi wile tawa tomo.
==God my remote control is stolen.
Could you get that to me. i want to go home.
poki wawa pi jan lawa sewi ni li kama lupa anu seme?
ona li ilo lon awen tenpo, taso tenpo ni la ona li pona ala.
==This God's battery went down or what?
It worked for a while and then choked.
sina wile toki e seme?
==What do you mean?
mi toki e ni: o sin e poki wawa.
==I mean put in a new battery.
o, ona li kepeken poki wawa ala.
==Hey it doesn't work with battery.
ni la tan seme la ona li ilo ala?
ona li pakala tan tomo pali anu seme?
==Then why it doesn't work.
it's a Manufacturing defect?
mi pali ala e ijo pakala.
==We don't make defecting  piece.
sina pali e jan lawa sewi ni anu seme?
==you made this god?
a. kepeken luka pi mi sama.
==Yes. With my own hands.
sina pali e jan lawa sewi anu jan lawa sewi li pali e sina?
==you made God or God made you?
jan lawa sewi li pali e mi mute ale.
taso mi pali e sitelen ona.
==God has made us all. We have just made
their sculpture.
tan seme la sina pali e sitelen ona?
==Why do you make their sculpture?
kepeken ni la mi ken lukin toki tawa ona
e ijo pi pilin ike mi.
==So that we can pray and
could talk to them about troubles.
sitelen ni li jo e ilo toki anu seme?
kepeken seme la toki li tawa ona?
==Does it have some sort of transmitter.
How the messages reach to him?
jan lawa sewi li wile ala e ilo toki.
ona li kute e mi mute ale kepeken ala.
==God doesn't need a transmitter. He
hear us all directly.
ona li kute kepeken ala, la tan seme la
jan li wile e sitelen ni?
==If he hear directly then what is the need
of these sculptures?
o, nasin seme la jan li ken pana e pona tawa jan ni?
==Oh man what to do with him?
sina wile weka e esun mi?
==you want to close my shop?
sina pilin ike tan seme a?
==What is your problem anyway?
jan akesi li weka e ilo lawa mi. mi wile kute tan jan lawa sewi,
taso ona li toki sin ala tawa mi.
==My remote control is stolen i am asking God
but he is not telling me anything.
jan o, sina jan nasa anu seme?
==dude. you (PK) drunk?
sina wile toki e seme?
==what you mean?
o, sina pana e pali pi mute ike tawa jan lawa sewi lili ni.
ona li ken ala tawa wawa lon monsi pi jan akesi
kepeken noka lili ni.
==hey how much overload you'll give to this little god?
How he is going to run and chase the theif with
such little feet?
o kama lon insa pi tomo pi nasin sewi. ni la jan lawa sewi suli li lon.
ona li tawa wawa li pali tawa sina lon tenpo lili.
==Get inside the temple there is a bigger God.
He'll run faster and do your job quickly.
o pana e kili ni e mani. ona li pali.
ni la o pana e Lupi 200 tawa mi.
==Give this coconut and some money and he'll do the job.
now give me 200 rupees.
jan ale li awen li jo e kili e mani,
kepeken ni la jan li pali tawa ona.
==Everyone was waiting with a coconut and money
inorder to get their work done.
==pini pi tenpo suli la mi kama nanpa wan.
After 2 hours my turn came.
jan lawa sewi o pana e ilo lawa mi tawa mi.
==God..God please get me my remote.
ona li lon seme?
==where is it?
o tawa. o tawa.
==come on. Move.
taso mi wile e ijo, mi kama ala jo e ona.
==but i didn't get what i wanted.
mije o. ona li pali ala tawa mi,
mi pana e mani a.
==Hey mister. He is not doing my work,
I even deposited the fee.
pali li kama.
==Will be done.
lon tenpo seme?
==When?
kepeken seme la mi ken toki e ni tawa sina?
pali li kama. o awen.
==How can i tell you that.
It will be done. have patience.
o pana e nasin. o tawa.
==Give me the way. Move.
taso tenpo seme la mi kama jo e ijo mi?
==But when will i get my thing?
o sinpin ala lon nasin. o awen tawa.
==Don't block the line. Move futher.
taso jan lawa sewi li pana e ijo mi
tawa jan ante, la seme?
==But what if God will give my stuff
to someone else?
sina jan nasa anu seme?
==you pk (drunk)?
meli o awen. sina pali e seme?
taso seme la mi kama jo e ijo mi?
==madam, just hang on. what are you doing?
but where will i get my stuff?
lon tomo pi pona lawa
==In mental hospital.
kepeken seme la ni li ken? mi pana e mani lon ni,
jan li pana e ijo lon tomo pi pona lawa anu seme?
==How is that possible. I gave the cash here
and delivery in mental hospital?
o tan insa e ona.
==Get him out of here.
ni la o pana e lipu taso tawa mi.
==Atleast give me the receipt.
o pana e lipu tawa mi.
kepeken ona taso mi ken pana e lukin pi ijo ni:
mi ken kama jo e ijo mi.
==give me the receipt.
If someone will ask at Mental hospital
what will i show as a proof?
o tawa weka.
taso ilo lawa mi?
==Get off.
-but my remote?
mi ken ala kama lukin e len noka mi.
==I can't find my chappal (mule)
ken la jan ante li weka e ona.
o jo e len noka pi jan ante.
tomo pi nasin sewi la tan en tawa ni li lon tenpo mute.
==Someone might have taken it.
you take someone else's.
In temples such rotation is common.
ona li kama jo e mani, taso
ona li pali ala tawa mi.
==They took the payment but
didn't do my job.
nimi ona?
==his name?
Lawa Sewi.
==Bhagwan (God)
ale nimi?
==Full name?
mi sona ala e ale nimi.
==i don't know the full name.
tomo ona li lon seme?
==where does he live?
lon poka pi tomo pi nasin sewi.
==In the near by temple.
sina pana e mani tawa luka ona anu seme?
==you gave money in his hands?
ala. mi pana tawa poki ona.
==No. I put in his box.
ona li toki e ni: ona li pali tawa sina?
==Did he say he is going to do your job?
ike li ni:
ona li toki ala.
==That's the problem.
He doesn't talk.
tan seme? ona li ken ala toki anu seme?
==why? is he dumb?
ken la a.
==Maybe he is.
ona li seme lukin?
==Tell me his appearance.
sama ni.
==exactly like this.
taso ona li suli sin.
==Only bigger in size.
o tawa ni.
==come here.
sina jan nasa anu seme?
==Are you PK (drunk)?
a. taso tan seme la jan ale li sona?
==Yes. but how does everyone know?
mi mute ale li ken lukin ala anu seme?
==Are we all stupid?
sike suno 20 la mi jan pali pi nasin lawa.
mi wile e tenpo lili taso, kepeken ona mi kama sona e ni: jan li nasa anu seme.
==I am working 20 years as a police.
takes me a second to know whoever is drunk.
jan Kipa Sin o.
o lukin lon ona.
==Kripal singh.
Search him.
o lukin e insa ona.
"jan sona Temelo."
==See what's in it.
-Dr. Demello.
jan sona o, tan seme la sina moku e telo nasa pi mute ni:
sina pini sona e nasin sewi sina?
==
Doctor, Why do you drink so much
that you even forget your religion?
sina tawa insa pi tomo pi nasin sewi ike.
sina wile e ni, jan li utala, anu seme?
==Instead of church you went inside
temple? do you want a riot?
sina o tawa tomo pi nasin sewi sina,
tawa jan lawa sewi sina.
==you should go to your church,
to your own God.
nasin sewi mi?
==church?
taso ijo mi?
==but my stuff?
tan ike sina la jan lawa sewi li kama moli lon tu palisa, taso sina...
==because of your sin, the god is being crucified, and you...
kama moli lon tu palisa? lon tenpo seme?
==crucified when?
lon kama pi sike suno 2000. tan ike sina.
==2000 years ago. for your sins.
taso mi pali e seme?
mi kama lon ni lon tenpo ni taso.
==but what did i do?
I just came here.
sina jan nasa anu seme?
==you PK (drunk)?
a.
==yes.
jan lawa sewi li lukin e nasin sina.
==God is watching your behavior.
jan lawa sewi li lon seme?
==Where..where is the god?
seme li lon poki ni?
==What is in that vessel?
telo nasa.
==wine.
tenpo ni la mi kama sona e ni: jan lawa sewi li pilin e kama ala tan telo kili.
tan ni la ona li kama pilin pona tan telo nasa, taso ni li ijo pi mani mute.
==Wine.
Now i understood God became bored with coconut water,
now he started enjoying wine and it was expensive.
tan ni la mi kama alasa e mani.
== so i started gathering money.
mi kama jo e mani wan tan tomo tawa pi tawa musi,
==Some money i got from that dancing car.
e mani ante tan jan pona ni, ona li lon supa nasin,
kepeken ni la jan li ken tan e mani lon wile.
==..and some from that generous man standing
on the bridge so that people can take as much as they want.
jan Pawisa o, poka ni la
tomo pi nasin sewi li lon anu seme?
==bhaaisaab, Is there around a
house of God somewhere?
a. ona li lon lukin.
==yes its right in front.
o awen. seme li lon insa ona?
==wait.
what's in it?
telo nasa.
tawa jan lawa sewi.
ona li lon seme?
==Wine.
For god.
Where is he?
meli wan li pilin ike tawa lukin.
mi luka e luka ona, kepeken ni la mi ken kama sona e tan.
==One madam seemed very sad.
inorder to know the reason i held her hand.
jan jaki o! sina lukin kama lon meli pi mije moli anu seme?
==Jerk! Trying on a widow?
kepeken seme la mi ken sona e ni: ona li meli pi mije moli?
==how do you know she is widow?
sina ken ala lukin e len walo anu seme?
==you don't see white saree?
mi pilin ike tan ni: mije sina li moli.
==So sad that your husband died.
seme? lon tenpo seme?
==what when?
kepeken seme la mi ken sona?
sina a li jo e len walo.
==how am i supposed to know.
you are the one wearing white.
kama pi kulupu unpa la jan ale li jo e len walo.
==In marriage everyone wears white.
ala. walo li ilo tawa tenpo pi moli jan.
==no white is when someone dies.
len pimeja li ilo tawa tenpo pi moli jan.
jan nasa o. o kama weka.
==black dress is when someone dies.
Stupid. Get lost.
kama nasa a! mije 3 sina ale li kama moli
lon tenpo sama anu seme?
==what a co-incidence. All your 3 husbands
died at the same time?
o, mi awen lon.
==hey i am still alive.
jan li noka mute e mi. pini ni la mi kama sona e ni:
jan lawa sewi li wan ala, taso ona li mute.
==After lots of punches and kicks i realized that
there isn't a single God in this planet but instead many.
jan lawa sewi ale li jo e nasin lawa pi ona sama.
==Any every God has its own rules.
jan lawa sewi ale li open e kulupu pi ona sama.
jan li pana e nimi "nasin sewi" tawa ni.
==Every God has opened their own company.
People were calling it religion.
nasin sewi ale li jo e jan lawa pi ona sama.
==There was a different manager for each religion.
jan ale li wan pi kulupu pi nasin sewi.
==Every man in this planet was attached to one religion/company.
jan ni li tawa lon monsi pi jan lawa ni taso.
==and that person was strictly following that one manager of
the company only.
ni la mi wan pi kulupu seme?
tawa jan lawa sewi seme la mi o lukin toki?
==Now which company's member am i?
which God should i pray?
ni li suli mute, kepeken ni la
mi ken kama jo e ilo lawa mi.
==In order to get my remote knowing this was
very important.
sina pali e seme?
==What are you doing?
sitelen tawa li lon seme?
==Where is the hallmark seal?
sitelen tawa seme?
==Which hallmark seal?
sitelen pi nasin sewi anu seme?
==The religious seal?
jan lili li wan pi kulupu seme?
kepeken seme la jan li ken kama lukin e ni?
==Which company this child belong to..
How would one find that?
jan lawa sewi li lon seme e sitelen ona?
==Where does god put his stamp?
mi wile kama lukin e nasin sewi mi.
taso tawa mi la ni li kama ala pali.
==finding my religion
was turing out to be impossible.
kepeken wan ni taso la mi ken kama pali pona:
mi kama lukin toki tawa jan lawa sewi pi nasin sewi ale.
==Now there was only one way..
to start praying Gods of all the religion.
wan ona li jan lawa sewi mi a,
ona li kute e mi.
==One of them must be my God.
Who'd listen to me.
nasa suli li lon, jan lawa sewi o.
==There is a big confusion god.
mi sona e ni: ken la mi pakala e ijo,
tan ni la sina ken ala kute e mi.
==I am making some mistake for sure
that you can't hear me.
o wile kute e pilin ike mi.
==ask my trouble
ante la o lawa taso e mi.
==Atleast guide me.
o.
please
mi o luka e luka mi anu
mi o anpa e lawa mi anu seme?
==Should i hold my hands or
should i bow my head on your feet?
mi o kalama e ilo kalama anu
mi o kepeken ilo wawa, kepeken ni la mi ken pini e lape sina.
==Should i ring a bell or
use a loudspeaker to wake you up?
mi o tawa lon monsi pi jan toki sewi kepeken lipu pi nasin sewi?
Should i follow geeta, kuran or bible?
jan lawa sina ale li toki
e ijo ante.
==Every one of your manager says
something different
jan wan li wile e pali ni: jan li moku ala lon tenpo suno "Mun".
jan ante li wile e ni lon tenpo suno "Mun Seli".
==Some asks to fast on monday and some tuesday.
jan wan li toki e pona ni: jan li moku lon kama pi tenpo suno.
jan ante li toke ni lon pini pi tenpo suno.
==some says to eat before sunrise, some after sunset.
jan wan li toki e pona ni: jan li lukin toki tawa soweli.
jan ante li toki e pona ni: jan li moli e ona li pana e ona tawa sewi.
==some says to pray cow, some says to sacrfice it.
jan wan li toki e pona ni: tomo la jan li jo e len noka.
jan ante li toki e ike pi ni sama.
==Some says to wear boots in your house,
some says don't.
mi ken ala kama sona e ni: mi o tawa lon monsi pi jan seme?
==I can't understand who to follow.
mi kama pilin utala tan ike pali, jan lawa sewi o.
==it has become frustrating, God.
mi wile e ni taso: mi tawa tomo.
sina wile kama lukin e ijo tan mi, la
mi pali e ona tawa sina.
==I just want to go home.
I'll do whatever you say.
o tawa e mi. o.
==Just let me go home. please.
o toki.
==Say something
wan pi sina mute o toki.
==somebody amongst you, answer me please.
o.
==please.
sina pini e lupa tan seme?
==hey why you locking?
tenpo suno ni la sina tawa ala.
==i won't let you go today.
o open e lupa. mi wile tawa.
==open the door, i have an entry.
sewi Siwa. ona li pakala e ike
li pilin ike tan ala.
Shiv, who is the sin destroyer.
not afraid of anything.
jan lawa o! sina jan seme?
==gone. who are you?
tenpo ni la sina sona ala anu seme?
mi jan Na Sa.
==didn't recognise me?
I am PK.
jan lawa o! jan li lon ni anu seme?
jan nasa li lon ni. mi wile pana e musi lon poki pi ko jaki anu seme?
==Security. anybody there?
-Drunk person is here. Shall i do skit in the toilet?
o open e lupa... o open!
==Open the door..now
nanpa wan la o pana e ilo lawa mi.
==first get me my remote.
ilo lawa seme?
==which remote?
pi tomo tawa mun.
==Spaceship's.
tomo tawa mun?
==spaceship?
sina weka anu seme? tenpo mute la mi toki e ijo ona.
==Forgotton? I told you so many times.
mi tan ma ni ala. mi tan ma pi poka ala.
==I am not from this planet,
came from far away.
sina pana e ilo lawa tawa mi, la mi tawa tomo mi.
==Just get me my remote and i'll go home.
o weka e mi tan tomo ni.
mi mama pi jan lili.
==brother let me go,
I have small children.
mi sona pona e ni.
==i know it very well.
sewi Kane en sewi Kate. ona li lili ala li ken lon poka ala sina.
==Ganesh and kartik. They aren't little and can survive alone.
sina pana e ilo lawa mi, la sina ken
tawa kulupu mama sina.
==you get me my remote and then
go to your family.
sewi o weka e mi tan ni.
==Oh god save me.
sewi ante li sewi tawa sina anu seme?
==there is a God above you?
[toki sewi Palata]
==Om namah shivaya
ona li lon seme?
==where is he?
o weka e mi tan ni!
==Save me!
jan o pana e pona!
==Somebody help!
mi lon nena Imalaja... li pilin e sewi.
==I was in the himalaya..meditating
ni la suno li kama
tan ijo lili ni lon anpa.
==..then suddenly i see light,
from this small object on the ground.
mi pini e lukin mi li pilin e sewi.
sewi li suno e mi.
==I closed my eyes thought about God,
and i got enlighted.
ijo ni li seli mute. taso ona
li lon lete mute.
==this object was so hot even in
a very cold weather.
sewi li toki e ni: ijo ni li wan tan
ilo kalama pi jan lawa Siwa. o kama jo e ona.
==God confirmed its the broken piece of
lord shiva's pellet drum. embrace it.
o pana e ona lon tomo sewi. lukin ona li kama
e pona tawa jan li weka e ike tan jan.
==take it and put it in a temple. its auspicious
sight will take people's trouble away.
sina wile lukin e ona anu seme?
==would you like to see it?
o sewi e jan lawa Siwa.
==praise the lord shiva.
jan lawa Siwa o! kama sewi!
==Lord shiva, miracle!
o pini!
==stop.
o pini ala e ona. ona li pilin wawa.
==Let him come, he's excited.
jan lawa Siwa o, pona!
==Lord Shiva, Greetings
o tawa ni ala. o kama.
==not there, here
o kama li toki e ijo pi wile sina.
==Say what you want to say here.
sewi Siwa li suli.
- sewi Siwa li suli.
==Shiva is great.
-Shiva is great.
jan lawa o, sina lon seme?
o kama lon ni li kama suli tan toki mi.
==Lord where are you hiding?
come upfront, accept my gratitude.
ona li lon ni!
mi lukin e ona lon tomo pi ko jaki.
mi wile kama jo e ijo mi la ona li tawa wawa.
==He's right here.
found him in the toilet.
when i asked for my property, he ran.
tawa mi la ona li weka. taso ona li pana e mi lon ni
tawa ijo mi.
o sewi e jan lawa!
==I thought he escaped but he brought me here
to my property.
praise the lord!
sewi Siwa li jo ala e ni. mi a li jo.
ken la pana pi ijo ni li pakala.
==Its not shiva's. its mine.
Might have been a cross delivery.
ijo sina li lon ante. sewi li sona e lon ni.
sewi li lon ni.
sewi o kama tawa sinpin.
==yours must be lost.
Ask the lord. he is here.
come in front lord.
pona. mi kama jo sin e ijo mi.
==Its ok i will take my property.
Since when you feel you don't
belong here?
you should meet a psychiatrist.
Madam time to go. the punishment worth
500 rupees is over.
one moment.
here's my card. I could get you
meet a psychiatrist. call me.
tawa sina la toki mi li lon ala anu seme?
==you think my story is fake?
tan ni la o tawa li pana e toki pi soweli Niku
lon ilo pana. ijo pona li kama ala lon nasin sina.
==so go on telecast nikku dog story
on tv. you aren't lucky enough.
jan Pante Si o, mi wile toki e ijo sin tawa ona.
==pandey ji. I want to meet him once
more.
sina pana e mani sin, la
mi pana a e ona tawa sina.
==Instead give me 500 rupee more
and take the whole man.
tawa mi la mi toki ala e toki pi soweli
pi lukin moli tawa sina.
==i don't remember telling you about
suicidal dog.
sina toki ala a.
==because you didn't.
sina sona kepeken nasin seme?
==how did you know?
sina jo e luka mi, la mi lukin e insa pi lawa sina.
==I read your mind when you held my hand.
tawa sina la toki mi li lon ala. tan ni la
sina wile toki e ijo pi soweli Niku.
==you thought my story is bogus,
you have to manage with nikku dog now.
o toki e lon! mi toki a e ona tawa sina.
==don't lie. i must have told you.
jan pi ma mi li pilin e luka li lukin e lawa.
ma ni la jan li toki e nimi pi lon ala.
==people in my planet touch hands and read minds.
here people use false words.
o pana e luka sina tawa mi.
==here let me show you.
ala a!
==No way.
mije sin o pana e pona. meli mi li ike lon tomo pi pona sijelo.
ona li wile e mani pi mute suli tawa pona ona.
mi wile e mani lili taso.
==Help me son. My wife is sick in the hospital.
they need 10000 rupees.
I am short with 500 rupees.
sina pana e mani lili ni, la...
- mi pana.
If you will give 500 rupees..
-I'll give.
pona!
- o toki e tomo sina tawa mi.
mi pana e mani sama tawa sina.
==There you go.
-Write me your address
i will return.
sina ken ala pana e mani tawa tomo mi.
o awen poka ona.
==its impossible to send money
where i live. you keep it.
mije sin o pona mute.
==Thank you son.
jan suli o kama jo e mani lili
tawa jan pali.
==Uncle! keep 100 rupee more
for the tip.
ale pona tawa sina!
==long live son.
sina toki e lon ala a. ona li nasa e sina.
tomo pi pona sijelo li lon ala poka.
==its proved now that you were lying.
he made you fool. there is no hospital
nearby.
mi sona. ona li tawa e meli ona tawa
tomo pi mun luka.
==I know. he brought his wife for
treat to a 5 star hotel.
tenpo suno ni la meli ona li sike suno sin.
tenpo pini ala la ona li lon tomo pi mun luka.
==Today his wife's 75th birthday.
She's never been to 5 star hotel.
tenpo suli la ona li awen e mani pi kama jo ona.
meli ona li wile e suwi lete sin.
==gradually he was collecting money from
his pension. wife ordred an extra ice cream.
taso ona li jo ala a e mani. toki ona la
ona li tawa tomo telo. taso ona li kama tawa mi.
==he went out of money. he gave bathroom as
an excuse and came here.
pakala suli.
==what a crap.
sike mi la jan li toki e lon taso.
pilin sina li ante ala e ni.
==in our ball nobody lies.
believe it or not.
ni li sike suno sina a.
o musi!
==Its your birthday after all.
Enjoy.
Told you nobody lies in my
planet.
did you tell anybody?
you didn't tell anyone that you
are alien. right?
No No. if i had they would caged me
in a laboratory for experiment.
then why trusted me?
Since the day i came here,
everybody took money from me.
you were the first one put money for me in the donation box.
I got a feeling that you are gentleman.
can be trusted.
I'll get you your remote.
how?
how i don't know.
but you will go back home for sure.
i promise.
what for you gazing?
aliens don't visit me often
after all.
Do everyone in your planet has
such weird ear?
yes
and everyone stay naked?
don't you find weird?
that crow is sitting naked. looks weird to you?
it be weird if will wear a tie.
PK i kept thinking whole night
how to get back your remote from tapasvi.
-hello!
-hello, connect me to balbir singh room no. 4.
wrong number.
-its not fortis hospital?
-I have been telling you since yesterday
its a wrong number.
-how could it be wrong number.
I myself saved it in the mobile phone.
so what did you think?
hello connect to balbir singh, room no. 4
you called so late, he died this morning.
what?
but how could someone die in
haemorrhoids operation?
yeah that's strange. but ok we will write in
death certificate it was heart attack.
family reputation should not be spoiled.
-come take the body.
-yes yes..umm on my...
-BYE.
why you said that?
spreading happiness.
He will have a good surprise once he'll see
his friend alive.
I fed up with his wrong numbers.
so just duped him.
duped?
PK i was just kidding.
I understood now the whole case.
Someone is duping.
whoever dials God's number for trouble via tapasvi
never reaches God cuz he is duping everyone.
Tapasvi ji is a fraud here.
who dials wrong number.
and someone sitting above is duping people.
who is not a God.
otherwise why would God call my remote
their property?
I feel..
..the communication system between God and people
in this planet is completely wrenched.
that's why all managers ( gurus) call is going
to a wrong number.
meaning?
that's why god was giving me illogical
solutions to my problems.
Sometimes he say come to my house rolling
on the road then i will do your work.
now tell me aren't we god's children?
so normal parents would never tell their
kids to do such horrible things.
your father ever told you if you
need a new dress you should roll on
the floor?
sometimes says shower me with cow's milk
everyday. how illogical.
Pk..if these cals would have reached the right number..
..then what would he say?
he would have said give milk and food to the
poor people.
..why on earth you showering me with milk?
I am sure someone is duping people like
you did on phone.
Pk thought tapasvi was honest.
but i didn't say a word.
i had an idea..
an idea that would get PK's remote.
who is this PK?
his identity is unknown.
but he has a unique imagination.
mean?
- it means that..
if he'll spot you smoking
he'll call police saying you are doing suicide.
because packet states "smoking kills"
what is the point?
War.
I want to collide tapasvi ji with PK on tv.
it will be a one on one debate.
jaggu..
i already have marks on my right butt.
do you want it to be balanced out
on the left butt too?
No.
the highlight of this debate will be
that PK will not fight with tapasvi.
Pk will just explain nicely that their
prayers are going to a wrong number.
tapasvi will have no idea how to
answer him.
cherry..cherry..
he is here. just meet him once.
I challenge you, even you
can't take away his confusions.
trust me. please.
it fell from your pocket.
its not mine.
kamasutra, strawberry flavor.
I hate strawberries man.
ask someone else. its not mine.
what a weirdo.
is it yours?
-How dare you?
- check your purse maybe something i missing.
- dickhead.
- uncle is it yours?
- No not mine.
Pk. that's his.
whatever you want to ask, ask him.
come.
what's this?
its condom.
what's it use?
it controls world population.
how?
by  putting it on.
..while having sex.
how  is it controlled
if you'd put it?
Not if i put it on.
millions of people wear it.
do you give this everyone?
everyone got it.
I have a question.
please go ahead PK.
When money is dropped,
everyone claims its mine.
..but when condom drops,
everyone denies. why so?
buddy sex is a very private subject.
why?
nobody announces the world that today
i am having sex.
then why in marriages..everyone announces the
whole town with firecrackers & loud speakers..
that today i will have sex.
what happened?
I dont have a reply to that.
..but i do have a job for you.
lets leave before he changes his mind.
you better hide your butt now tapasvi,
because my trishul (weapon) has launched.
Pk..tapasvi ji meets everyday with their follower
here. and pass their messages to God.
we'll go in and listen to their phone calls.
the moment you feel the calls are reaching
wrong number, you start explaining
tapasvi ji.
then he'll return my remote?
the day he'll understand someone is duping,
and that object is not god's.
he should return it.
ok i will explain.
to make someone's house is virtue.
and to make god's house is the greatest virtue.
donate in abundance.
and get rid of all your troubles.
say it devotee. what bothers you?
tapasvi ji..my wife is paralysed since 6 months..
doctors can't help her..
i want that you..
God, show him the right path.
direction..
as you say god.
have you heard of rathong glacier?
no
Its in himalaya, catch the train and go
to siliguri.
..from there in bus to gangtok..
from there..
by foot. it would take 8 days.
In kanchenjunga mountain there is a
huge god's temple.
go there.
your job will be done.
its a wrong number.
what it is?
wrong number.
tapasvi ji. the technology you are using to reach
god is fused.
all calls are reaching to wrong number.
..and there is a duplicate god sitting there
who is duping you.
what..what are you trying to say?
i'll explain.
we all are god's child right?
yes. so?
..so if your child comes to you with his problem.
what would you do?
solve his problem. yes?
or would you say..
2000 km. away i have one more house.
visit me there and explain me the same
problem once again.
then i will resolve. how illogical.
if call would have reached the right god,
he must have said take care of her.
why left her and chasing me?
once you will die, we will meet.
atleast now spend time with her.
right?
i can prove. someone is duping here.
call the god again.
do you give guarantee that aunty will
be fine?
uncle, get written confirmation first.
don't leave aunty without it.
call now. everything will be clarified.
its time for tapasvi ji's silence meditation.
that duplicate god told you that
my thing is yours.
its not god, but fraud.
its fraud.
till now nobody has seen or heard about god.
what god wants, his managers tell us.
Pk raised an important question today.
what?
Do god really hear his managers.
no
the solutions is created by god or any fraud.
coming from wrong number.
so pk what should public do?
till the telephone problem fixed.
talk to each other and resolve problems.
help each other.
pk has a point.
we should boycott these managers.
instead support each other. just like...
pk says this temple should not be build because
that object is his.
what's in your pocket?
you smoke?
yes
and alcohol too.right?
occasionally.
you drink and smoke after knowing that it kills.
government gives permit.
factory makes this poison.
its sold opening in shops.
..yet nobody objects.
when in this holy ground we want to construct
a temple then why objections?
if you want to ask question, ask PK.
is he muslim?
or some anti hindu religion?
you must ask PK these questions.
and about his religion.
mehmood gajni came many years ago.
..to destroy temples.
today once again somebody came.
can you call your god?
he wants to know my religion right?
first ask him what religion do their these
kids have.
is it a joke?
call me and ask.
its easy even i can answer.
he's christian, he's sikh, he's jain and
she's from your cast.
could you reveal now?
hello, i am sikh.
i am muslim.
i am jain.
i am christian.
and i am jagat janani. sikh.
confused?
i changed their cloths randomly.
religion connection is with fashion.
let me show you.
beard and moustache means
sikh.
take out turban so hindu.
if exclude moustache
then muslim.
This difference is made by wrong numbered
god.
had it been real god. he would have put
his stamp on your body.
do you have any?
mine?
what are you gazing? take off your
cloths and check.
why shy?
come on all for tapasvi ji.. take off cloths and
check your body for stamp.
why shy? ok i do first.
watch.
do you see any religious stamp?
do you see? wait let me take off...
security.
what are you doing?
let me prove.
that's not god's object.
jaggu.
finish this.
you were 40 days old when tapasvi gave
you your name.
keep in mind he can give name,
then ruin your name too.
papa, he gave me the most ruined name.
jagat janani.
you. how much money you want?
-papa
-you're harassing tapasvi ji for money?
no.
you will burn in hell.
have some fear from god.
thank you..papa. thank you.
i had incomplete knowledge.
Now i know everything.
this whole game is about fear.
wrong number god is not just duping but
taking advantage of our fear.
whatever you know. could you
explain papa?
ofcourse. come.
i don't have time for this non-sense.
papa. deal. if it'll turn out to be non-sense.
i will shut the show.
papa, this college has exams.
all students are terrified.
now we'll start here business from fear.
- come i will show.
here's the machine in factory.
some investment.
here's the inauguration.
now watch.
in 15 minutes investment is double.
there you go.
this is how it begins.
tea.. hot tea.
look in tea business there is
more investment.
bicycle, cup, sugar, tea-pot, gas etc.
and here..a stone and red color.
tea..tea..hot tea.
there you need to call customers.
and here you have to blow them away.
move, give others chance too.
there you need to bow to customers.
here customers bow to you.
look,
if someone is really scared he'll lay down completely
wrong number god is doing business.
business of fear.
he knows, the one who scares
goes to temple.
you are also very coward.
take this all off.
don't stand against religion.
its about faith.
if god wanted that we don't raise
questions then he wouldn't give us common sense.
these religious businessmen when can't answer,
gets violent.
scares us and surpress us.
but now we won't be quiet.
now more pk will arise.
friends, if you see anyone dialing wrong number,
make their video and send us. we'll broadcast it on tv.
ask questions, spread awareness
one question, if you can emerge gold out of no where,
when why don't you help poor?
when you can emerge gold by yourself,
then why ask donation from us?
its a wrong number.
- jaggu come with me.
- wait
- just come with me right now.
you guys are on fire. whole world is sending
wrong number videos.
they said feed cow and you'll get job.
is this cow will upload my resume on job websites?
its a wrong number.
more
he said become christan otherwise god will send you to hell.
if god wanted he would have made me born in christain family.
now why making me change religion.
wrong number.
they all want to go to school.
now there is a fatwa, if girls go to school,
kill them.
god can't be so mean that he has problem
with their future.
its wrong number.
whatever is in our destiny,
will happen.
god has made only one masterplan for
whole universe.
you must accept that.
outside temple your followers are selling your
holy books in very cheap price.
here if you read this 4 lines, you will have
a new born son.
it means get a 10 rupee book, read 4 lines and screw up
the whole nature cycle.
pk, your show is hit.
whole word is texting.
here, one more.
what happend?
dad sent message,
he is ashamed of me.
i was very little when i wrote my first
poem for dad.
i look like mother, says everyone.
its true.
but i am the daughter of my daddy.
i narrated this poem in annual day.
every parents in the crowd, applaud.
amongst those clapping, my dad was whistling
nonstop.
clapping stopped, but whistling didn't.
he was so proud of me.
and today he wrote he is ashamed of me.
he has some kind of illusion.
the day he'll have clean mindset, he'll whistle
non stop yet again.
that day will never come.
knock it off, come.
i will show you what one does when
in sorrow in my planet.
here follow me.
just copy me to get your battery recharged.
..and what are you doing exactly?
close your eyes.
-then how will i copy you?
point. let it open then.
mi lukin e sina. mi awen e sina.
mi pali ala e ijo ante li awen lon monsi sina.
==gazing you, bearing you,
i forgotton everything and just follow you.
ni li weka tenpo a.
olin li weka tenpo.
==this is such a waste of time,
love is a waste of time.
ni la tenpo wan pi lon mi anu tenpo mute la
mi weka e tenpo mi. olin li weka tenpo.
==then also i decided atleast once in this life,
i will waste my time. love is a waste of time.
tenpo mute la mi lukin e mi. tenpo mute la mi pona e linja mi.
==many time i see mirror and do my hair.
tenpo mute la mi ante e len mi. tenpo mute la mi telo pi kon pona e mi.
==may time i changed my cloths and put deodrant.
mi pilin e ijo nasa lon pilin mi.
mi ken ala toki e sona ona.
==weird and unexplained feeling in my heart.
not sure how to describe.
mi jo e sinpin pi pilin pona tan ala.
mi sona ala e ijo lon ni.
mi pilin sama ni: mi tawa sewi li pana e kalama wawa.
==I smile without reason,
not sure what is going on.
feel like flying and shouting.
donation box has more questions than
money guru.
all your products have stopped selling.
facebook and twitter is full
of negative comments.
only five?
these are positive.
rest bulk is with profanity.
do something,
we can't stay hidden long time.
call him.
now its our turn to ask questions.
tapasvi wants to come to our show.
-what?
make pk ready.
don't forget to watch,
one more question at 6 pm.
my friend has become star.
he stays naked in public.
i made him star.
jackass is sitting in tv.
and me here in this filthy place, in a
smutty bar, drinking disgusting alcohol with a dumbass like you.
made him star. bullshit!
pk bhairosingh called, asking
for you.
brother.
licentious boy. you have become a star.
brother, where are you?
Now i am mandava,
but i am coming tomorrow along with a gift for you.
The theif who stole your thing is in my abduction.
he sold your stuff for 40000 rupees.
ask to who.
-to who
-to tapasvi ji.
god said its a broken piece of lord shiva's drum.
god said take it and situate it in a grand new
holy temple because its presence..
hello, what happened?
the thief who stole my remote is caught.
brother said, theif sold it to tapasvi ji.
then tapasvi is in trouble.
lets take thief to tapasvi ji, and ask him
to return remote otherwise we will reveal the truth
by theif on television.
tapasvi ji didn't find my remote in himalaya.
that means he is lying.
that means wrong number is spread by
tapasvi ji not duplicate god
did you know about that?
pk, remember the first time you
talked about wrong number?
whoever is trying to reach god, tapasvi ji
is dialing wrong number for them.
i knew in a second that you were
not doing it right.
but i didn't clear your confusion.
because if you call tapasvi ji fraud
his follower would've beaten you.
people needed an creative
solution.
hold on. that's wrong number.
and your examples with wrong number
really pulled mass attention.
today they are all supporting you.
- its a wrong number.
Pk my plan worked.
we almost got your remote.
you will leave tomorrow.
i'll never see you again.
will miss you.
i will really really miss you.
should i stay?
don't joke.
i am serious.
I have a job.
will apply for residence permit. will settle here.
for sure somebody would want to
waste her time with me.
will get married.
who'll marry you?
why?
how would some girl introduce you?
meet my husband. he is pk (drunk) haha
that's not my name.
everyone bullshits.
- pk haha
- i will change my name.
why don't you suggest me some name.
whichever you like.
you see name and personality should match.
absolutely. so how is my personality?
i will show you the demo.
- in difference of name and personality..
- oh i am in no mood of a poetry.
- have you ever paid attention between your name and personality..?- how to explain her.
name is so different and so is your personality.
- fire man is so cold
- quiet man has once told.
doesn't have a tail behind still the name is hanuman.
in arjun lal house bow and arrow is not found.
phool chand is so extra fat,
jet can't fly in which he sat.
brilliant.
i got some address card.
choose one suitable name for me.
look inside, which one is the best.
tandlu ram chittey
i'll pass
tutari singh...pfff..
ssshhh...pfffffffffffff
sarfaraz
sarfaraz..
- what happened?
look further for bestest...
name.
what happend jaggu?
nothing.
[train approaching]
hey brother.
[song playing on radio]
one terrorist group was resposible for this attack
..they said it was only an example.
nobody can mess up with our religion.
..we may save our religious belief till we are alive.
where are you going?
to the show
its not important..leave it
its very important now
welcome to the show "one last question"
lets welcome pk and..
- one moment.
give me ..
what is this?
what is this, god says this is his.
but he says it's his property.
God says contruct temple,
but he obstructs.
now who shall we follow?
GOD or him?
he was wearing yellow helmet
and distributing this..
have a look
first he stated God is missing,
later called him fraud.
tomorrow he might say
god is dead.
son, what are you upto?
..a world where god doesn't exist?
Do you have a clue about common people's
pain.
..there is no food to eat
no house to live.
no friends to talk..
many commit suicide everyday
cut their wrist,
hang themselves on ceiling.
..because they don't have hope.
if worshing god..
..following customs and praying gives them hope
then who are you to take
their hope away?
and if..
..you really want to detach people from god,
then tell us what would you give us in return?
enough of these "wrong number" allegations.
instead tell us today what exactly is the
right number.
you are right
once even i didn't have food to eat..
no place to live
i used to cry a lot
..as i didn't have any friends
either.
that time i only had one support
..God.
every morning felt like tomorrow
will be less worse, god will do something.
i agree..
that believing in god gives hope.
..gets strength to cope with pain.
but i have a question.
which god to trust?
you say god is one.
i say wrong..
there are two gods.
one who created us
..and second whom you created.
i don't know anything about the one
who created us.
but the one you created..
is exactly like you.
small, liar, corrupted, makes false
promises.
he meets rich quickly,
and makes poor wait in queue.
gets happy when appreciated.
frighten people over small things.
I have a simple point.
trust god who created us.
and strike out the fake god you created.
and you think we'll stay quiet?
Son, we know how to protect our god.
you will protect god?
..you?
this planet very small
million bigger planets are out there in
space.
and you are sitting in that small planet,
in small city, in small room, talks about protecting god?
the one who created this whole life?
he doesn't need your protection.
he can protect himself real good.
today somebody tried to protect their god
and my friend died.
only this shoe is left.
stop protecting the god, or else in
this planet only shoes will be left, no humans.
one muslim blows a bomb
and one hindu guru is listening your lecture.
nice.
where is the stamp to prove that you
are hindu and i am muslim?
this difference is created by mankind.
and that itself is the most dangerous wrong number
of this planet.
due to this people die.
the same wrong number you struck in jaggu's
brain and separated her from sarfaraz.
what wrong number?
that sarfaraz is dishonest.
you told that muslims are dishonest.
so he cheated. where's the lie?
one second.
-no hang on. what is going on?
hang on one moment.
so you are telling me that my prediction was
wrong?
duh, ofcourse.
then prove it.
prove it that my prediction was wrong.
and if you couldn't..
you would lay on my feet and beg for
forgiveness.
or if i prove it then?
pk don't.
then this is yours.
challenge accepted.
could we point the cameras at jagat janani?
we hope you would co-operate with us
and tell the truth.
you fell in love in belgium with a pakistani man.
yes or no?
why are you discussing my
personal life in public?
on friday 3:21 pm i predicted that..
he'd deceive you.
and next day..
you went to marriage registrar office,
but this man didn't come.
yes or no?
yes he didn't come.
now can you please stop this?
now..would you bring yourself to my feet,
or shall i bring my feel there?
sarfaraz didn't cheat.
pk let it go, please
no please tell everyone what exactly
happened.
pk please.
just once,
for my sake.
I was waiting and a letter arrived.
did sarfaraz himself delivered?
no
he sent through a kid.
did it have any name on it?
noooo.
then how did you know it was sarfarz's
letter?
it could've been for some other woman.
place didn't have another woman?
there was one with a cat.
and she gave you cat to carry.
kid who delieved letter,
did he know you?
No
did you know him?
no
then how would he know that
he should give letter to you.
perhaps he's been told to deliver letter
to woman with cat.
he gave you letter. you read..
and didn't even call sarfaraz later?
did you call him?
no. because tapasvi ji struck wrong
number in your brain.
that muslims are dishonest.
sarfaraz didn't cheat you jaggu.
what's going on here?
dog, cat.. you will keep inventing stories
and we'll stay quiet?
one moment.
the truth will be revealed now.
call sarfaraz.
the number does not exist.
any other number friend, college, something?
come on jaggu..
Belgium university.
pakistan residence number.
don't have.
- think jaggu darling.
I do part-time job in pakistan embassy.
he was working part-time in pakistan
embassy.
call pakistan embassy and put on speaker.
Greetings, pakistan embassy.
hello..umm did you ever had sarfaraz yousuf from lahore
working for you?
Is your name jaggu?
hello is your name jaggu?
yes but how did you know?
everybody..she called from india.
jaggu called from india. come here.
Miss, sarfaraz yousuf calls us every
morning at 9:00 am.
and gracefully asks only one thing..
that someone from india named jaggu
called today?
we say no and he disconnects. made us
completely mad.
hold on, we'll connect you to him.
[phone rings]
hello
- mr. sarfarz yousuf?
- yes, greetings.
where are you calling from?
umm from lahore, why?
where are you right now?
i am at my home. why?
do you have any chair or bench
around you?
if yes please sit down, because
you may fall after shock.
pardon me, i didn't get you.
there is a call for you from delhi.
there you go, have a word.
- hello
- sarfaraz!
jaggu
jaggu is everything ok?
did you come to the marriage registrar
office?
- yes i did.
but you left.
why did you never call?
how could i ? I found your letter stating
never contact me.
I knew you had a huge pressure from
your family.
but not sure why i always felt you'd try to contact
me someday.
you are terribly late.
what i could've done?
I had wrong number.
just got a right number from a friend.
Thank you son.
hold this for a sec.
PK, you taking batteries with you?
- yes i don't get it there.
but what would you do with so many
batteries?
i'll listen to the voices recorded in cassettes.
what kind of voices?
voices of your earth's birds, crows and traffic.
you'd listen to traffic noise?
I would do that when i'll miss
your planet.
wait up, i have one more trunk to unload.
pk let it go.
how could i let it go? there are
more batteries.
do you hear me?
driver, do you hear?
in your planet everyone has
such weird ears?
everyone stays naked?
what are you looking at?
is there any dirt on my face?
you know i was in 10th when i wrote
my first poem?
for my dad.
i look like mother everybody says,
everybody says, they say truth..
poetry means less words,
deep meaning.
by the way you are really cute.
one more toast for a friend, who...
[jaggu singing]
there wasn't any bird, crow or traffic..
every tape had only my voice.
[tape scrambling]
got it.
prick made me run a lot.
what did you record in it, pk?
told you so, bird, crow and traffic.
when ever your earth would rotate,
i will play this tape.
I will wave hand vigorously.
you also wave hand..
..if get time.
it doesn't have my voice right?
your voice...
it is.
one of your poetry is there.
only one poetry?
ofcourse, why would i waste my time completely on you?
after all i don't love you.
he didn't look back even once.
perhaps he was hiding his tears.
he learned some and
taught some.
he learned to lie.
and taught the true meaning of
love.
love me enough, to let me go.
he also came here without cloths..
just like a newborn child.
He also used to ask millions questions
just like a child.
and then oneday
he was gone.
around 4000 million k.m away.
at the end he gave me two
beautiful gifts.
sarfaraz
and my father.
i will gaze at his star till i am
alive.
and wave.
i am sure he'll do the same.
i miss him.
one year later..
brothers in an hour we'll land
on earth.
don't forget what i taught you.
only four major points.
1. its prohibited to walk naked there.
this kissing stuff and naked tasks are
being performed unseen,
behind four walls.
thing which is allowed in public are
fight, war and cussing etc.
2. biggest confusion here is language.
if you hear in market that i'd like
chicken/fish.
that doesn't mean they love animals.
it means they'll eat them for lunch today.
we will research why there is a difference
in what they speak and think.
3. we'll steal cloths from the dancing car
right after landing.
then please insert your remote in your
underwear.
..really really deep inside.
don't want anyone to steal.
and 4. most importantly if you meet someone
who says he can help you contacting God.
..then to hell with research. just take a U-turn
and run for your life in full speed.
come bro, don't be scared. come.
what for you gazing? eh?
I have a question.
what?
last time how many times you
got beaten up?
what's that for?
self defense.
aha, safety!
let's go
-yes let's go.
not that direction.
this direction...
subtitle created by
-Arpan Bhatia-